JOE WILES: We're coming in with 38 which is the "House of the Rising Sun" by The Animals.
Let's take a lot at the guitar.
Now before we begin this song, you're going to want to be familiar with a few chords.
The first one is an A minor chord.
It's an open A string, 2nd fret on the D string, 2nd fret on the G string, 1st fret on the B string, and the open high E string, strum from the A string down, okay?
Next one, is going to be a C major chord, 3rd fret on the A string, 2nd fret on the D string, open G-string, 1st fret on the B string and the open high E. The next one is going to a D major chord.
Open D string, 2nd fret on the G string, 3rd fret on the B string, and 2nd fret on the high E string.
Next one is going to be a F major chord, 3rd fret on the D string, right here, 2nd fret on the G string, and then with your index finger, pad both the 1st frets of the B and the E string, okay?
The last one you want to know is an E major chord.
Open low E string, 2nd fret on the A string, 2nd fret on the D string, index finger with your 1st fret on the G string, then open B, open E, okay?
Now, get very familiar with those chords.
Make sure you can switch between them with some fluency, okay?
In the next segment, we're going to put them altogether in order in the progression of this song with kind of an interesting right-handed strumming pattern, okay?
I'll see you in that segment.